<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guilherme Nemeth</title>
    <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guilherme Nemeth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:30:45 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glhrmfrts.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compiler Devlog #1 - Stack-based Intermediate Representation (IR)</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/posts/compiler-devlog-1-stack-based-intermediate-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:30:45 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/posts/compiler-devlog-1-stack-based-intermediate-representation/</guid>
      <description>Prologue So I started writing a compiler around a year ago, worked on it for about a month or two and then lost interest as with most of my side-projects&amp;hellip; tsc tsc.
Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, there&amp;rsquo;s very little reason to write a compiler nowadays, if any. Hardware has gotten so powerful and software has gone so complex that we should all just use what&amp;rsquo;s already there. I feel like a Baby-Boomer born inside a Millenial body, because I miss the &amp;ldquo;good old days&amp;rdquo; (when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even conceived yet).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:10:27 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a hobbyist musician since 2011, you can find a list of my music projects below:
 Urania: Post-rock band with only 1 single released :&#39;). Corardor: Mostly vaporwave and avant-garde weird stuff. Slugcat: Math-Rock and Midwest Emo inspired project. gnemeth: Mostly dark ambient OSTs for my Quake maps.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:10:23 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/programming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a professional programmer since 2014, I have worked with numerous web technologies, starting from PHP then moving to Python / NodeJS on the back-end, and Angular / ReactJS on the front-end. Today I work mainly as a systems programmer using C/C++, and as a mobile developer using Kotlin/Swift.
You can find a list of my programming projects below:
 porter: Asynchronous HTTP client for C++(17) using libcurl. gattlib: A fork of gattlib (BLE communication library) with fixes and improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quake</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/quake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 22:10:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/page/quake/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a hobbyist level designer for Quake, you can find a list of my maps and mods below:
 Celestine Cistern A map for the Blue Monday Jam, where the goal was to build a map with blue visuals.
 Download   Humming Tunnels A map for the Speedmap Snack Pack, an episode built in under 24 hours.
 Download   Terrainformation A map for the Speedmap session #210, &amp;ldquo;overgrown&amp;rdquo;-themed maps built under 48 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
