<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guilherme Nemeth</title>
    <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guilherme Nemeth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 21:10:06 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://glhrmfrts.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyroads clone (devlog #2?) - Super-early Alpha v0.1 Build</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/post/skyroads-clone-early-super-alpha-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 21:10:06 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/post/skyroads-clone-early-super-alpha-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a little more on my spare time on the game. This build still has some bugs but it&amp;rsquo;s playable
I think, so there you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vxs0wnecti4ett2/tns.zip?dl=0&#34;&gt;Windows 64-bit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the game gets more complete, I will eventually add builds to other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a name yet, so ignore the TAIHO thing in the intro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship model is temporary, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit well with the environment, I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have Java installed and you are not on Windows, you can download from the link above and run the &lt;strong&gt;.jar&lt;/strong&gt; in the folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyroads clone devlog #1 - 3 months</title>
      <link>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/post/skyroads-clone-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glhrmfrts.github.io/post/skyroads-clone-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s christmas evening and I&amp;rsquo;m here writing my first devlog. I decided to do these because I think I can keep better track of my progress and it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to share ideas, it might come to be useful for someone someday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I want to talk about a game I have been working on for about 3 months now, which is much more time than I ever did work on a game.
As you can tell by the title of this post, it&amp;rsquo;s a Skyroads clone/remake, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what game Skyroads is, you should definitely look up, it&amp;rsquo;s
a pretty fun game from the good old DOS times. Originally made by Bluemoon Interactive, Skyroads is a remake itself from an older game from the same
developer called Kosmonaut, it&amp;rsquo;s one of that games that is &amp;ldquo;easy to learn, hard to master&amp;rdquo; with the gameplay being pretty much you guiding a
space ship while having to jump some blocks in space, simple right? Well, I advise you to confirm that by yourself ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My version of Skyroads is pretty faithful to the original, I only made it prettier and will possibly add some more features in the future, but I really
need to focus on getting the gameplay solid right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tools:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing the game using &lt;a href=&#34;https://libgdx.badlogicgames.com/&#34;&gt;libGDX&lt;/a&gt;, which is a Java framework for cross-platform games,
It&amp;rsquo;s the framework/library that I am most familiar with, so I&amp;rsquo;m feeling pretty confortable with the development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also use Blender for modeling the ship&amp;rsquo;s 3D model, every model until now has been hard-coded into the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-game-looks-like-now:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;How the game looks like now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written too much and showed you nothing, so here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s4.png&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s6.png&#34; alt=&#34;6&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://glhrmfrts.github.io/skyroads-devlog-1-s7.png&#34; alt=&#34;7&#34; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;No roads for Andromeda :c&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Taiho&amp;rdquo; is just a temporary name that I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember what it means. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t come up with a final name, so I&amp;rsquo;m accepting suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-code-looks-like-now:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;How the code looks like now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, not great, in fact, pretty ugly. I actually started writing this game more than half a year ago, but gave up after 1 month, and then I started working on it
again in the middle of November, and my coding style has changed a lot in that short period of time, lots of bad design choices like functions receiving arguments that it
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even know it exists, separation of concerns, general code organization, etc&amp;hellip; I wish I had started writing this as an engine and only after I had a working engine
I should start writing the game itself, but no, everything is mixed up and you can see gameplay code together with physics simulation. Can I fix that? Of course. Will I fix that? mmm, probably not.
I just have this feeling that I need to &amp;ldquo;ship the product&amp;rdquo; as fast as possible because it has been so much time since I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; a game (last was in June 2015) that I need to prove to myself
that I&amp;rsquo;m able to finish this as quick as possible. After that, I will start working on a new game from scratch, and focus on writing a proper game engine first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;todos:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;TODOs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish the gameplay mechanics (tile effects, etc&amp;hellip;), I&amp;rsquo;m almost done here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a proper 3d model for the ship, I still want it to be pretty basic, but anything is better than the fucking rectangle that it is now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a level editor, editing level files by hand is pretty boring right now, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll polish it enough that I will leave it there for players who want to build their own levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make more worlds, there is only &amp;ldquo;Red Heat&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Andromeda&amp;rdquo; at the moment, need to come up with some A E S T H E T I C S for the rest, I plan to have 6 worlds, each with 3 roads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for controllers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize the renderer post-processing pipeline, I’m already mentally preparing myself for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully it will be done by March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;Open source&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is not open-source at the moment, I think it hasn&amp;rsquo;t reached a level where it might be useful for anyone yet, specially for the grotesque mistakes that I&amp;rsquo;ve made.
But I will make it open-source in the future, I just hate when small games like this are not open-source, as ugly as the code maybe, they are still a great source of learning
for people who want to get into game development and see how that particular game was made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:8b6050b405ba0e6e352990bee6800a74&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that is it, this is the project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on to practice game development, if you liked it, stay tuned for more devlogs. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also, merry christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>